Kartheek Surampudi

#501, Vaishnavi Mahal, Road Number 12, Aklapuri Colony, Hyderabad, 500035 (IN) +91 8328290111 kartheek2000mike@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Happy coder and open source contributor. Experienced in building and facilitating end-to-end ML pipelines. In-depth knowledge and use of software technologies to include Python. Extreme attention to detail and ability to multitask within fast-paced environments.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C++, Java

Machine Learning: ONNX, Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV, Pandas

Databases: Postgres SQL, DynamoDB, Rockset

Web Technologies: Django, Node.js, RESTful APIs, FastAPI

Deployment: Docker, Kubernetes, Microsoft Azure

DevOps: Github Actions, Kubeflow

EXPERIENCE

Sep. 2021 – Present Remote

Senior Machine Learning Engineer, ScaleTorch

- Architechted and implemented key services to include, the core of the platform that handles concurrent ML training experiments accross clouds.
- Lead the team that built services to facilitate fault-tolerant ML training workloads accross clouds and regions.
- Built a data streaming engine to move training data around economically.

Apr. 2021 – Sep. 2021 Hyderabad, Telangana

Jun. 2019 – Oct. 2019 Hyderabad, Telangana

Jun. 2019 – Aug. 2019 Hyderabad, Telangana

May. 2019 – Jun. 2019 Hyderabad, Telangana

IVA Engineer, SmartCow

- Working on Nvidia Jetson Devices
- Building streamlined applications that bring AI to the edge.

Machine Learning Intern (Remote), AITS

- Worked on deepC- a framework for deploying neural nets for edge devices.
- Implemented ONNX operators
- C++ and Python Integration with Swig

Python Intern (Remote), cppsecrets.com

- Developed a Disk Health Monitoring system based on SMARTCTL which can scale up to thousands of systems in a network.
- Wrote articles on python and machine learning.

Software Developer Intern, DRDL

• Worked on and maintained the production side of a huge database of defense employees.

- Fixed issues across multiple packages in both frontend(JSP) and backend(Java).
- Traced out rare and problematic bugs.

PROJECTS

COVID-Kicker

Python, Tensorflow, Kubeflow, MS Azure

COVID-Kicker is a deep learning-powered REST API that detects COVID-19 from X-Ray images. A Kubeflow pipeline automatically retrains the model periodically to keep up with the data.

pyParallelMR

Python

pyParallelMR leverages the fact that greater speeds in computation can be achieved using more memory. It is a simple queue based map reduce engine which executes tasks in a batch wise parallel manner. The project can be found here.

Presence: Facial Recognition based attendance system

Python, Django, OpenCV, MS Azure, Android

Presence is a facial recognition-based attendance tracker meant for schools and colleges. A teacher has to take a picture of the class instead of calling each student's name. The demo can provide further details.

Disk Health Monitoring System

Python, Smartmontools

This project is an "all-python" solution to monitor the disk behavior of a set of computers(all if required) in a network. This application was built on top of the smartctl utility by smartmontools. The demo can provide further details.

EDUCATION

Jun. 2021

Bachelor of Technology: Information Technology

• Swami Vivekananda Institute of Technology - Hyderabad, Telangana

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Finished in top 3 among hundreds of teams across multiple themes in the MishMash Hackathon.
- Won first place out of 20 teams in a 24-hour hackathon at IEEE Fest by developing a shopping cart website that sorts products based on reviews (NLP).
- Selected as one of 50 teams statewide for a project expo for innovative ideas to solve real-world problems.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree by Udacity
- Deep Learning Specialization (5 courses) by Coursera
- Advanced Python by LinkedIn
- Intel® Edge Al Scholarship Foundation Course Nanodegree Program by Udacity
- Applied Al with DeepLearning by IBM
- VSD Machine Intelligence in EDA/CAD by Udemy

WEBSITES AND OTHER LINKS

- Github https://github.com/k4rth33k
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartheek-surampudi-0a535a163/
- Portfolio https://k4rth33k.github.io/